Your future is in its hands.
The Terminator is a action, thriller, science
fiction film directed by James Cameron.
In the post-apocalyptic future, reigning tyrannical supercomputers teleport a cyborg assassin known as the "Terminator" back to
1984 to kill Sarah Connor, whose unborn son is destined to lead insurgents against 21st century mechanical hegemony.
Meanwhile, the human-resistance movement dispatches
a lone warrior to safeguard Sarah.
Can he stop the virtually indestructible killing machine?
Terminator, played by Arnold Schwarzenegger.
Kyle Reese, played by Michael Biehn.
Sarah Connor, played by Linda Hamilton.
Traxler, played by Paul Winfield.
Vukovich, played by Lance Henriksen.
Matt, played by Rick Rossovich.
The Terminator is a 1984 American science fiction action film directed by James
Cameron, written by Cameron and Gale Anne Hurd and produced by Hurd.
It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger as the Terminator, a cybernetic assassin sent back in time from 2029 to 1984 to assassinate Sarah Connor (Linda Hamilton),
whose not-yet-conceived son will one day save mankind from extinction by Skynet, a hostile artificial intelligence, in a post-apocalyptic future.
Kyle Reese (Michael Biehn) is a soldier sent back in time to protect Sarah.
The screenplay is credited to Cameron and Hurd,
while co-writer William Wisher Jr.
received an "additional dialogue" credit.
Cameron devised the premise of the film from a fever dream he experienced during the release of his first film,
Piranha II: The Spawning (1982), in Rome and developed the concept in collaboration with Wisher.
He sold the rights to the project to fellow New World Pictures alumna Hurd on the condition that she would produce the film only if he were to direct it; Hurd eventually secured a distribution
deal with Orion Pictures, while executive producers John Daly and Derek Gibson of Hemdale Film Corporation were instrumental in setting up the film's financing and production.
Originally approached by Orion for the role of Reese, Schwarzenegger
agreed to play the title character after befriending Cameron.
Filming, which took place mostly at night on location in Los Angeles, was delayed because of Schwarzenegger's commitments to Conan the
Destroyer (1984), during which Cameron found time to work on the scripts for Rambo: First Blood Part II (1985) and Aliens (1986).
The film's special effects, which included miniatures and stop-motion animation, were
created by a team of artists led by Stan Winston and Gene Warren Jr.
Defying low pre-release expectations, The Terminator topped the United States box office for two
weeks, eventually grossing $78.3 million against a modest $6.4 million budget.
It is credited with launching Cameron's film career and
solidifying Schwarzenegger's status as a leading man.
The film's success led to a franchise consisting of several sequels, a
television series, comic books, novels and video games.
In 2008, The Terminator was selected by the Library of Congress for
preservation in the United States National Film Registry.
The film explores themes of man vs machine, artificial
intelligence (a.i.), saving the world, laser gun, cyborg.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.